## Nahid Jahani

**QA Analyst** 

(604) 441-9287

jahaninahide@gmail.com

Coquitlam, BC

nahid-jahani.github.io/Nahid-jahani-Portfolio/

#### **Profile**

Energetic, practical professional with 4+ years of experience QA Analyst in manual and automated testing. Proficient in creating automated tests using Java, Selenium, and other scripting languages, with a deep understanding of web applications, APIs, Microservices, and backend systems. Demonstrated ability in identifying and covering gaps in test coverage by designing comprehensive test cases and scenarios. Proven skills in documenting, investigating, triaging, and re-testing bugs and failures, along with validating and signing off on daily and weekly deployments. Committed to championing quality standards and advocating for end-users in the design and assessment of new features and functionality.

#### **Skills**

- Manual and automated testing of websites and APIs
- Dedication to using quality standards and producing high-quality software
- Intrinsic drive and a proactive attitude toward assisting others
- Working knowledge of testing ideas and procedures
- Bachelor's degree in software engineering

- Ability to address complex challenges through critical and inquisitive thought
- Ability to extensively test features and apps with great attention to detail
- Capability to work alone or with others to solve problems
- Strong communication in both writing and speaking, including active listening in Farsi and English

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Operating Systems: Windows, MAC OS, Linux
- API: Postman
- Bug Tracking: Jira, Help
- Cl servers: GIT
- Programing language: C#, Java, React.js

- Web Related: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Web Testing Tools: XPath, Developer Toolbar, Android studio, Selenium WebDriver with Java, Robot Framework with Python, Postman
- Mobile: Android, iOS
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

### **Professional Experiences**

Quality Assurance Analyst - Manage Petro - North Vancouver, BC

Sep 2020 - Current

- Designed, documented, and executed test scenarios, identifying target test items, and scripting automated tests using Java, Selenium, and Python.
- Conducted automation testing across Web apps, APIs, Microservices, and backend systems, ensuring high-quality deliverables.

- Analyzed and identified gaps in test coverage, and designed comprehensive test cases and scenarios to increase test coverage.
- Championed quality standards, ensuring the team was following the proper acceptance criteria and leveraging the correct test cases.
- Validated work in production and signed off on daily and weekly deployments, managing staging and deploying changes in a complex, interconnected environment.
- Documented, triaged, investigated, and re-tested bugs and failures, collaborating closely with
  the
- development and management teams to identify and fix post-production bugs.
- Advocated for end-users when designing or assessing new features or functionality, partnering closely with Product Managers and Software Engineers.
- Played an integral role in setting up and refining QA processes, contributing to the robustness and effectiveness of quality assurance efforts.
- Tools & Environment: Java, Python, Selenium WebDriver, Postman, Jenkins, Jira, Git, MS-SQL
  Server, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

#### Web Developer- Faith Fire - Surrey, BC

Feb 2019 - Aug 2020

- Participated in code reviews, design reviews, and coding with much innovation
- Proficient in web technologies: HTML, CSS, client-server architecture, API
- Shared insights with the team and found tailored solutions for every problem
- Assist in resolving any defect escalations and locating ongoing quality control problems.

#### Web Developer Freelance – Various Employers – Vancouver, BC

Sep 2018 - Present

• Overall web design and implementation software for different projects such as Dice Game, New Test, Faith Fire, and Food Order

#### Certifications

Associate Certificate - in British Columbia Institute of Technology (BCIT) - Burnaby, BC

2018

#### **Education**

Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran

2014

# **Nahid Jahani**

# **QA Analyst**

(604) 441-9287

jahaninahide@gmail.com

Coquitlam, BC

nahid-jahani.github.io/Nahid-jahani-Portfolio/